{
  "reference_number": "10155",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "I support the Government setting an earlier target of 2040 rather than 2050. We need to aim high to achieve any kind of success. I\n support the Climate Change Commission advising on the specific target for 2050 as well as specific targets for the Government to set\n later. There are good reasons to seek advice from the Climate Commission about the 2050 target. In particular, the Commission\n\n could provide expert advice on complicated parts of the 2050 target, such as the “sustainable level” for short-lived greenhouse\n gases."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Long-Lived Gases and Stabilised Short-Lived Gases - Long-lived gases to net zero by 2050 while also stabilising short-lived gases",
      "answer_index": 12,
      "notes": "We need to have an ambitious goal if we are to achieve anything. We cannot expect to reach the ideal situation if we do not aim for\n the ideal situation."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "Relying on international carbon credits (even if the credits have integrity) creates uncertainty about what reductions need to be\n achieved in New Zealand. It also means we are investing in other countries’ low emission transitions, rather than our own."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "However, the 2050 target should only be revised in exceptional circumstances and following the advice of the Climate Change\n Commission experts."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Legally-binding budgets, set 10-15 years in advance so that 3 budgets are in effect at all times, at a level recommended by the\n\n Climate Commission and approved by Parliament, are fundamental to the Zero Carbon Act."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": "Budgets should only be revised in exceptional circumstances. It is not appropriate for an incoming new government to change an\nupcoming budget, which has already been set. This would create too much uncertainty and instability. A new government is able to\n\nintroduce different policies to meet the upcoming target."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "For example, it might be appropriate to change an upcoming budget after an extreme natural disaster (such as a major earthquake).\nRevising a budget in this situation would not mean changing the long-term 2050 target."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "This time frame should be 6 months after an emission budget has been set."
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The Government should consider the advice of the Climate Change Commission for all aspects of responding to climate change,\n\nincluding setting plans to meet emissions budgets. The Government’s policy plans to meet emission budgets should be\ncomprehensive, fair, cost-effective, environmentally sustainable, urgent and reflecting a commitment to Te Tiriti o Waitangi."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "As well as the expertise listed on page 45 of Our Climate Your Say, the commission should include expertise in public health."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Dear Minister I strongly support the passing of a legally binding climate law and the immediate creation of a Zero Carbon Act. I believe\n\nin a net-zero carbon future for New Zealand. We need to make dramatic reductions in our emissions to keep climate change limited\nto 1.5 degrees and protect our native flora and fauna, our societies and our important infrastructures for ourselves and future\n\ngenerations. We must act now to make a positive difference. The key things I support in a Zero Carbon Act are: • an ambitious Act\nthat follows the climate science by covering all gases across all sectors • a target of net-zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2040 •\n\nan Act that targets the emissions from transport, industrial activity, agriculture and all other sources • an Act that includes emissions\nbudgets that should be at least as important as fiscal budgets, with plans set by the Government to achieve these budgets • an\nindependent Climate Change Commission of experts to monitor emissions and give advice to the Government to keep New Zealand\n\non track for its emissions reduction goals. I support Zero Carbon Act legislation that establishes the goal of limiting warming to 1.5\ndegrees. We should not settle for 2 degrees warming. Any higher limit than 1.5 degrees would result in devastating impacts for Pacific\n\nIsland states and significant extinctions. That is not acceptable. To give us the best possibility of achieving no more than 1.5 degrees\nwarming by the end of the century, we must start making rapid cuts in all greenhouse gas emissions now. I support a net-zero target\n\nof 2040, with the majority of cuts occurring over the next decade. I support all greenhouse gases being included in the law,\nconsistent with international climate frameworks. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) clearly states that methane\nreduction is critical to succeeding in tackling climate change. Our climate law must include all greenhouse gases, including those\n\nfrom our biggest emitting sector - the agricultural sector. I support setting a gross emissions reduction target as well as a net\nemissions reduction target. We cannot rely on planting trees alone to offset our emissions. We must seek to decarbonise our\n\nindustry and transport systems. As the Parliamentary Commissioner for the Environment stated in their submission to the Productivity\nCommission, June 2018, page 4: “Each tonne of emissions offset by forestry is a tonne not reduced at source. Relying too heavily on\n\nforestry could lead to continued high levels of gross emissions. Pressure to reduce these after 2050 could entail a more costly and\ndisruptive transition than a deeper transition commenced earlier.” I support the ‘firewall’ principle that New Zealand’s targets must be\n\nachieved by actual reductions in our own domestic emissions and not through the purchase of overseas carbon credits or an over-\nreliance on forests as carbon sinks. I support setting legally binding climate budgets that are set at a bare-minimum ambition, which\nmust be achieved or bettered by government within the prescribed timeframes. While budgets should be binding, policy\n\nrecommendations from the Commission should be just that – recommendations. The world needs pathways to transformational\nchange if we are to avoid catastrophic warming. This is the scale of the challenge. The science is clear: the only way we can succeed\n\nis with big ambition. New Zealand must be bold and pass strong law for the sake of our precious earth and future generations. I\nsupport the establishment of a Climate Change Commission. The commission’s role should include: • devising binding climate\n\nbudgets • identifying the level of reduction for each form of greenhouse gas (long-lived and short-lived) • monitoring adherence to\nthe set ‘firewall’ • monitoring progress towards our targets • monitoring cumulative emissions • advising on adaptation. The Climate\nChange Commission should provide advice to the New Zealand government. To ensure transparency and accountability, I support\n\nthe Government being required to table all reports from the Climate Change Commission to Parliament. I support the Government\npreparing a National Climate Risk Assessment. The Government must be required to produce an Adaption Programme to address\n\nthe climate risks identified in the National Climate Risk Assessment.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
